# Mohammad Atikur Rhaman

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER · ENOSIS SOLUTIONS

Dhaka, Bangladesh

□ (+88) 016-8440-4468 | **☑** atikur.rhaman.cs@gmail.com | **回** Anikcsejnu | **面** atikurrhaman | **⑤** anik7258

## Summary.

As a very passionate competitive problem solver and developer, I am looking for an opportunity where I can use my passion for a good cause and for my own skill development. Currently working as a **Senior Software Engineer** at **Enosis Solutions, Dhaka**. **4+ years** of experience, specializing in desktop and web app development. Interested in devising better problem-solving methods for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

# **Work Experience**

**Enosis Solutions**Dhaka, Bangladesh

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2023 - Present

- Working on snmp agent project built in lua programmming language for a embedded system.
- Working in C++ based framework for cross-platform desktop applications QT and QML.
- · Working with one of the most extensive HID manufacturing teams in the world and their HID interaction software.
- Implementing requested features and fixing bugs on the current projects.
- · Analysis, breakdown, and distribution of the tasks related to a single feature following the Agile development process.
- · Collaborate with the teammates, Peer testing features, and peer review codes to help the team grow.
- Communicate with clients verbally and through JIRA as well for clarifications and queries.
- Worked independently on several extensive desktop applications for designing pressure vessels and creating industry-standard reports developed in Delphi, MS-SQL Server and Accuracer DB.
- Integrated AutoCAD Inventor with Pressure Vessel software to create full-fledged CAD drawings using Inventor API COM model in C#.
- Tools & Technologies: QT, C++, QML, Delphi, C#, VB, TestComplete, FitNesse, DUnit, SQL Server, Accuracer, FastScript, DevExpress, Git, JIRA.

**Enosis Solutions**Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2021 - Dec. 2022

- Contributed to a project containing several extensive (20+ years of development) desktop applications for designing pressure vessels and creating industry-standard reports developed in Delphi, MS-SQL Server and Accuracer DB.
- · Contributed to another prominent product that stores vessel welding information, and maintains the standard code documents.
- Implemented new features and bug fixes for these various desktop applications and designed unit tests by following the **Agile** development process and proper **design patterns and principles.**
- Implemented code changes on a **C#** based tool to communicate with the Delphi projects.
- Configured and troubleshooted the CI/CD and testing servers to maintain the system flow using TeamCity.
- Developed features and fixed bugs for a TSR application using Pascal script and writes dev regression test for UI testing using TestComplete
- · Communicated with clients and collaborated with team members through JIRA.
- Tools & Technologies: Delphi, C#, VB, TestComplete, FitNesse, DUnit, SQL Server, Accuracer, FastScript, DevExpress, Git, JIRA.

BJIT Limited Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (AI DEPT.)

Oct. 2019 - Dec. 2020

- Completed 3 months of professional training in Python.
- Developed an Unsupervised Image Search project from scratch.
- Implemented a custom automation engine with python that **reduces 80%** testing time.
- Performed R&D based task to improve required deep learning model accuracy.
- Tools & Technologies: Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning, Image Segmentation, Convolutions Neural Networks (CNN), Python.

# **Projects & Publications**

#### StepSians - An academic informative site for helping students

Dhaka, Bangladesh March 2020 - June 2020

WEB DEVELOPER

- This is an informative site for the student of an academic organization.
- Contribute to developing the features and review other's work as well.
- · Github Repo: Anikcsejnu/STEPS
- Tools & Technologies: Python, Django, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML.

## Performance Analysis and Mitigating the Challenge of Local Search

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Co-Author

Jan. 2019 - April 2019

• Research Paper Published on ICIEV 2019, USA. Paper DOI: 10.1109/ICIEV.2019.8858506

#### Skills

**Language** C, C++, QML, Pascal, C#, VB, GO, Python.

**Platform** QT, Delphi, .Net, Django, TestComplete, DUnit, Fitness, SQL Server.

**Technology** Accuracer, FastScript, DevExpress, Git, JIRA.

MARCH 14, 2024 MOHAMMAD ATIKUR RHAMAN

### **Education**

#### **Jagannath University**

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Jan. 2015 - Oct 2019

B.S.C IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

- CGPA after completion of the degree: 3.39/4.00
- Completed Courses [URL]

# **Additional Experience and Achievements**

#### **Competitive Programming**

Dhaka, Bangladesh

STOPSTALK: ANIKCSEJNU

Jun. 2015 - Present

- Runner up at BUBT BACS REGIONAL PROGRAMMING CAMP 2017(Beginner Level).
- Second Runner up at NUDB CSE FEST 2017.
- · Became champion and runners-up individually in several intra-university programming contests.
- Participated in 10+ onsite national programming contests including ICPC-2016, 2017, 2018.
- Solved 1000+ problems in different online platforms including Leetcode, Codeforces, Uva, CodeChef, Hackerrank etc.

#### **Volunteer Programming Triner**

Dhaka, Bangladesh Jan. 2017 - Oct. 2019

JAGANNATH UNIVERSITY

- Taught junior fellows about C and C++ programming language.
- Taught basic to intermediate level algorithms, data structures.